- [Instructor] If you've never heard the term MERN before
and aren't familiar with what it is this video is for you.
Otherwise, feel free to skip it.
MERN stands for Mongo, Express, React, and Node.
It's a full-stack approach to building your frontend
and backend with these tools and being able to build
a full application end to end.
Mongo is the database, a document based, non-SQL database
that works well with JavaScript-based applications.
A MongoDB database is one big object containing collections.
Each collection could be like a contextual item,
like for example, players for the database we'll create.
Then inside the collection we have documents,
which are the players themselves.
So, one player would be in a document,
another a second document, etcetera.
And then inside each document we have the data
for each players, such as a name, team,
contact information, etcetera.
The documents looks like adjacent object
with a key value pair approach or arrays of data.
Express is the web server part,
and how we're able to build a Node-based backend.
In other words, our frontend will interact with the backend
through the use of Express syntax.
React is the frontend and where we'll build the components
that will allow our users to add players
and see the list of players in the team.
And finally, Node is the main element
that allows all these pieces to fit together
and is the server technology that is used.
It allows Express to add its syntax on top of its server
and create a web server.
Although we won't go into a full-on course
for each of these elements, we'll delve deep enough
so we understand how each part interacts with each other
and what are their functional roles
as we build the soccer application.
If you're curious and would like to learn more
about each part, feel free to browse our library
as we do have in-depth courses for each one.